American Brass Company Records 1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
American Brass Company Records
undated, 1351-1978.
1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
224.5 Linear feet
The American Brass Company was founded in 1893 with the consolidation of five existing brass mills in the Waterbury, Connecticut area. Intended as a holding company, American Brass absorbed the following companies: Plume & Atwood Manufacturing, Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing, Waterbury Brass, Scoville Manufacturing, Holmes, Booth and Haydens, and Coe Brass Manufacturing. The collection dates from circa 1800 to 1978 and provides a unique view of one of the major brass producers in the history of the United States. The materials vary in type from newspaper clippings to minute books and ledgers dating from the early 19th century.
American Brass Company.
History
The story of the development of the brass mills in the Naugatuck Valley is the story of 19th century entrepreneurs who would found one firm, merge with another, then reorganize again to form new ventures. The American Brass Company was no exception; it was founded from many segments of the industry including the Aaron Benedict Company (est. 1812) and the various Coe companies.
Officially, the American Brass Company began 7 June 1893, when a group of men from five of the six brass mills in the Waterbury, Connecticut, met to consolidate their interests. The new company was intended to be a holding company for the following operations: Plume & Atwood Manufacturing Company, Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Company, Waterbury Brass Company, Scoville Manufacturing Company, Holmes, Booth and Haydens, and Coe Brass Manufacturing Company. However, it was to be another six years (1 March 1899) before the charter was accepted and the company finally organized. Even so, the principal companies could not agree upon remanufacturing activities. All of the companies, with the exception of the Waterbury Brass Company and the Coe Brass Manufacturing Company, withdrew from the newly formed consolidation. The Ansonia Brass & Copper Company (of the Phelps Dodge family) joined the remaining two, and on 14 December 1899 the three companies-- Ansonia Brass & Copper, Waterbury Brass and Coe Brass Manufacturing--formed the American Brass Company. By 1901, Benedict & Burnham and Holmes, Booth and Haydens had rejoined the venture and the American Brass Company was on its way.
The next two decades would bring major reorganizations to the company. On 1 January 1912, the holding company became an operating company and the associated companies were now divisions of the parent, American Brass Company. In 1922, the Anaconda Copper Mining Company (of Montana) acquired American Brass, although the company retained its own identity until 1960 when the name was changed to Anaconda American Brass.
The Anaconda Company merged with Atlantic Richfield in 1977. The American Brass files housed at the corporate archives were transferred to Los Angeles, CA, in 1981 when the headquarters of Anaconda American Brass Company were moved from Waterbury, Connecticut to Rolling Meadows, Illinois. The name of the division was subsequently changed to ARCO Metals. No administrative correspondence or records groups remained at Waterbury and the collection was divided into logical series at the corporate archives.
Scope and Content
The collection dates from circa 1800 to 1978 and provides a unique view of one of the major brass producers in the history of the United States. The materials vary in type from newspaper clippings to minute books and ledgers dating from the early 19th century.
Arrangement
Series I: Historical Materials ( undated, 1351-1978 ) is a collection of historical background notes used by Clark S. Judd to create his manuscript, "The History of the American Brass Company." Mr. Judd, a former president of the company, worked on this project from 1942 until 1959, when ill health forced him to put it aside for a time. He was assisted in his research by Russell H. Pope, an American Brass employee since 1912. The files contain clippings, anecdotes and general background information on the American Brass Company and the brass industry in general. Dates on the folders may refer to the event noted and not the actual document itself.
Series II: Administrative Files--American Brass Company (ABC) ( undated, 1848-1972 ) consists of general administrative files including minutes, opinions on reorganization in 1911 and land deeds.
Series III: Sales Department Files ( undated, 1853-1969 ) contains individual price list books and specification catalogs dating back to circa 1800. These materials were used by the company library for historical research and information on official company names, logos, letterheads and price information.
Series IV: Library Ephemera Files ( undated, 1642-1966 ) includes the company library vertical file maintained by Eulalia Madden, the company librarian. A mixture of primary and secondary source materials, the collection documents the history of the industry as well as the company. Of particular interest are such items as the Benedict & Burnham permit for the Centennial Exhibition (1876), biographical files on Anaconda and American Brass personnel, and correspondence from principals in the company, such as C. F. Brooker. As in Series I, the dates on the folders will sometimes refer to the event, and not the actual document.
Series V: Papers, reports, historical records and Advertising reprints ( undated, 1841-1968 ) is a collection of miscellaneous materials including an Appraisal Committee report of 1892 regarding the formation of the company, Aaron Benedict's "Bargain" books (incentive pay for employees) and Coe family correspondence.
Series VII: Photographs ( undated, ca 1841-1962 ) is the photograph collection. Containing over 200 images, the photographs date from circa 1841 through 1962. The images include daguerreotypes, mill exteriors and interiors, the Benedict & Burnham booth at the Centennial Exhibition, the Waterbury Water Wheel and the flood damage of 1955.
Series VIII: Bound Volumes ( 1823-1972 ) consists of bound volumes including minute books, journals, ledgers, cash books and other documentation of the American Brass Company, its predecessor firms and some subsidiaries. Also included are samples from the Wolcottville Brass Company, American Brass Company, Waterbury Brass Company, Holmes, Booth and Haydens, Coe Brass Manufacturing Company, Ansonia Brass & Copper Company, Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Company and the Ansonia Clock Company.
Note: Series I-IV have been completely reprocessed, resulting in more accurate dating of materials and the assignment of new box and folder numbers. Series V-VIII reflect the older processing. The finding aid will be updated as the reprocessing of each series is completed.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining to Connecticut businesses and industry. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the reference desk.
Separated Material
The following materials have been separated from the collection and cataloged:
Flood 1955 Dodd Call No. D 1759
Restrictions on Access
There are no access restrictions on this collection.
Custodial History
The American Brass records were transferred from California to the University of Connecticut in 1988 when the corporate archives closed.
Acquisition Information
The American Brass Company Records were donated by the Atlantic Richfield Corporation in 1988.
Administrative Records.; Ansonia (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Brass.; Ansonia, Conn.; Brass industry and trade--Connecticut.; Brass industry and trade--United States.; Bylaws.; Charters.; Connecticut--Business, industries, and trades--Brass.; Connecticut--Business, industries, and trades.; Copper industry and trade--Connecticut.; Copper industry and trade--United States.; Copper mines and mining--Montana.; Copper mines and mining--United States.; Corporate libraries--Connecticut.; Correspondence.; Deeds.; Financial Records.; Histories.; Land companies--Connecticut.; Leases.; Minutes.; Montana--Business, industries, and trades--Copper.; Naugatuck River Valley (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Brass.; Newsletters.; Notes.; Patents.; Photocopies.; Photographs.; Publications.; Real estate business--Connecticut.; Smelting--United States.; Stock certificates.; Warehouses--Connecticut.; Waterbury (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades--Brass.; Waterbury (Conn.)--Business, industries, and trades.; Waterbury (Conn.)--Land.; Waterbury (Conn.)--Libraries.; Waterbury, Conn.
- Series I: Historical Materials, undated, 1351-1978
  - Subseries A: Collected by Russell H. Pope, undated, 1596-1960
    - "Evolution of the American Brass Company" compiled by Russell H. Pope [includes information about industry predecessors], 1851-1960 (Box 1:1)
    - "Early history of brass making" by C.S. Miller, 1932, 1948 (Box 1:2)
    - American Brass Company History [by Subject:A - G], undated, 1596-1959 (Box 1:3)
      - Alloys, Active, 1956
      - American Brass Company, 1922
      - American Brass Co., History of, 1922-1953
      - American Brass Co., Organization, 1893-1899
      - American Brass Co., Predecessors, 1816-1957
      - Anaconda, Officers, 1957
      - Anaconda, Origin of name, 1875, 1882
      - Anaconda, Spearhead, 1922-1947
      - Anaconda, Subsidiaries, 1958-1959
      - Anaconda, Trademark, 1917-1931
      - Anaconda Company (new name), 1955
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Co., general history, 1918-1929
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Co., Capital stock, 1920-1954
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Co., Employees, 1938-1954
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Co., Executives, 1920-1955
      - Anaconda Wire and Cable, 1929
      - Anecdotes, undated
      - Benedict Nickel, 1883, 1902, 1912
      - Beryllium Copper, 1946
      - Board of Directors, American Brass, 1899-1955
      - Board of Directors, Annual meetings, 1933-1955
      - Brass manufacturers price reports, undated
      - Brass industry publications, 1911-1930
      - Buffalo Copper & Brass Rolling Mills, 1907-1908
      - Brooker, Charles F., 1893-1905
      - Calendar (perpetual), undated
      - Catalog, Price, 1912, 1922-1924, 1940
      - Coe, Robert, descendants of, 1596-1959
      - Competitors, 1921
      - Consigned accounts, undated
      - Copper Products Development Association, 1959
      - Dates of Warehouses, 1899-1956
      - Dates of Mill depots, 1950-1958
      - Dates, Conference of Nations, 1943-1955
      - Directors, American Brass, 1958
      - Discs, large diameter, 1955
      - District Sales Managers, 1949
      - Ducommun Metals and Supply Co., 1849-1955
      - Duraflex, 1956-1958
      - Employee Relations Department, 1959
      - Employee Relations, Waterbury Strikes, 1919, 1938
      - Employment figures, 1942-1950
      - Everdur, 1923
      - Fires, 1864-1893
      - Firsts, 1852, 1873, 1883, 1959
      - General office, 1912
    - American Brass Company History [by Subject:H - Z], undated, 1778-1960 (Box 1:4)
      - Hine Coiler, 1887
      - Historical memoranda, 1857-1878
      - Historical data, 1823-1863
      - Historical notes on Phosphor Bronze, 1807-1956
      - Kettles (Brass), history of in U.S., 1812-1958
      - Main office, departments, undated
      - Manufacturers of non-ferrous products, 1912
      - "The Metal Industry", 1903-1940
      - Muntz Metal, 1832-1927
      - Names of persons who may have data, 1906
      - National Brass & Copper Co., Lisbon, OH, 1905
      - Newspapers, 1844-1903, 1922-1926
      - Obituary notices of American Brass employees, 1926-1952
      - Odds and Ends, 1778-1851
      - Opinion survey of employees, 1959
      - Order v. Shipment basis, 1912-1933
      - Original tenants, Waterbury, 1913
      - Patents and Trademarks, 1871-1878
      - Pension Committee, 1955
      - Personnel, Sales, 1950-1959
      - Personnel, U.S. government, loaned to, 1917-1955
      - Phosphor Bronze historical notes, 1807-1956
      - Phosphor Bronze miscellaneous, 1948-1949
      - Plants, oil paintings, 1944-1949
      - Pope, Russell H., 1912-1960
      - Ratcliffe (Metals) Ltd., J.F., 1959
      - Reference books on history of brass industry, 1926-1927
      - Research and Product development committees, 1958-1959
      - The River Company, 1905, 1912
      - Rolling of brass and copper, 1880-1905
      - Ruling book history, 1912-1955
      - Sales Offices and warehouses, 1955
      - Sales outlets during Weaver's assignment, 1912, 1922, 1941
      - Selling personnel, 1944-1955
      - Teflon hose assemblies, 1956-1958
      - "Thoughts in behalf of the American Brass Co.", 1936
      - Trademarks, 1922
      - Tubes, Seamless, 1889-1914
      - Waterbury Brass Company, 1845-1899
    - Historical notes and articles (A - M), undated, 1893-1957 (Box 1:5)
      - American Brass Company
        - Branches: Torrington, Waterbury, Ansonia, 1935
        - Chronology, 1893-1955
        - Departmental Correspondence, 1949
        - General Overview, 1948
        - Historical Write up, 1957
        - Products, 1946
        - Salute, 1947
      - Articles
        - Cowles, Alfred A. excerpt from "Copper and Brass" Abstract included, undated
        - Coe, John A. "Development of the Brass Industry,", 1939
        - Encyclopedia Americana extracts of brass, copper, and brass industry, 1947
        - Jacobs, Charles B., Jr. Historical Data, 1957
        - Kelley, C.F. "Address on 150th anniversary of Brass Industry in Waterbury,", 1952
        - Miller, C.S. Historical Notes, 1931
    - Historical notes and articles (O - T), 1823-1954 (Box 1:6)
      - Articles
        - Olson, C.F. "History of the Brass Industry in the United States,", 1823-1826
        - Skowronski, S. "Early History of Copper Mining in New Jersey" (Lecture), 1953
        - Tobin, James E. "The history of the Brass Industry,", 1954
      - Biographical Information
        - Israel Coe, Lyman W. Coe, John A. Coe, 1826-1921
      - Copper and Brass Industry
        - History, 1823-1926
        - Overview, 1823-1937
      - Domestic brass mill industry, 1925-1958
      - Merger of American Brass and Anaconda Copper
        - Excerpt from C.S. Judd's history, 1823-1926
        - General overview, 1930
    - Seamless Brass and Copper Tubes, 1956 (Box 1:6)
    - Torrington history, 1737-1935 (Box 1:6)
    - Torrington land records, 1834-1911 (Box 1:6)
    - Trademarks, historical information (compiled), 1958 (Box 1:7)
    - Charles F. Brooker, speeches by and about, 1914, 1927 (Box 1:8)
  - Subseries B: Division Histories, undated, 1802-1978
    - Aluminum - Terre Haute and Anaconda, 1955-1959 (Box 2:9)
    - American Flask & Cap Co., Fabricated Metal Goods, 1869-1871 (Box 2:9)
    - Anaconda Metal Hose Division, 1908-1959 (Box 2:9)
    - Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1905-1959 (Box 2:9)
    - Ansonia Brass & Battery Co., Ansonia Division, 1845-1869 (Box 2:9)
    - Ansonia Clock Company, 1850 (Box 2:9)
    - Ansonia Land & Water Power Co., Ansonia Division, 1869, 1899-1903 (Box 2:9)
    - Benedict, Aaron, Waterbury Division, 1812-1873 (Box 2:9)
    - Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Co., 1812-1955 (Box 2:9)
    - Benedict & Burnham Brass & Copper Co. of Illinois, Kenosha Division, 1901 (Box 2:9)
    - Birmingham Brass Co., Ansonia Division, 1892-1903 (Box 2:9)
    - Brown's Copper & Brass Rolling Mills, New Toronto, Ontario, Anaconda American Brass Ltd., 1900-1914 (Box 2:9)
    - Buffalo Brass & Copper Rolling Mills, Buffalo Division, 1907-1912 (Box 2:9)
    - Chicago Brass Company, Kenosha Division, 1905-1951 (Box 2:9)
    - City Manufacturing Co., Benedict & Burnham, 1851-1880 (Box 2:9)
    - Coe Brass Manufacturing Co. (subsidiary of Wolcottville and Torrington firm, Ansonia), 1909, 1934 (Box 2:9)
    - Detroit Brass & Copper Rolling Mills, Detroit Division, 1880-1958 (Box 2:9)
    - French Manufacturing Co., Waterbury, French Small Tube Division, 1905-1955 (Box 2:10)
    - Hastings-on-Hudson Branch, 1870-1959 (Box 2:10)
    - Holmes, Griggs and Smith Brass & Copper Tube Factory, 1860-1952 (Box 2:10)
    - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, Waterbury Division, 1853-1907 (Box 2:10)
    - Leavenworth, Haydens and Scovill, Waterbury Division, 1942-1958 (Box 2:10)
    - McCombe, Gault, 1919-1945 (Box 2:10)
    - Mad River Land records, 1922 (Box 2:10)
    - Mad River Real Estate, 1924 (Box 2:10)
    - National Brass & Copper Tube Co., Inc., Hastings-on-Hudson Branch, 1917-1925 (Box 2:10)
    - National Conduit & Cable Co., Hastings-on-Hudson Branch, 1880-1958 (Box 2:10)
    - Osborne and Cheeseman, Ansonia, CT, Ansonia Division, 1858-1892 (Box 2:10)
    - Pope Island Manufacturing Corp., Waterbury Division, 1959 (Box 2:10)
    - Porter & Company ( Abel Porter), Waterbury, CT, 1802, 1822, 1929 (Box 2:10)
    - Randolph & Clowes, Waterbury, CT, Waterbury Division, 1886-1955 (Box 2:10)
    - River Company, Waterbury Division, 1895-1959 (Box 2:10)
    - Thomas Wallace, Ansonia, CT, Ansonia Division, 1848-1883 (Box 2:10)
    - Wallace and Sons, Ansonia, CT, Ansonia Division, 1848-1893 (Box 2:10)
    - Waterbury Brass Co., Waterbury, CT, Waterbury Division, 1851-1952 (Box 2:10)
    - Waterbury Homes Corporation, 1916-1930 (Box 2:10)
    - Waterbury Brass Goods Corp., Fabricated Metal Goods Division, 1845-1956 (Box 2:10)
    - Wolcottville Brass Co., Wolcottville, CT, Torrington Division, 1841-1960 (Box 2:10)
    - "History" data, 1937-1941 (Box 2:11)
    - Historical material including financial artifacts, 1889-1960 (Box 2:12)
    - Brass industry historical records, 1952-1978 (Box 2:13)
    - "The American Brass Company Reference Book" [TM], 1850-1955 (Box 2:14)
    - Summary Book of Officers and Statements of various companies, 1900-1910 (Box 2:15)
    - American Brass Co., Main office, 1958 (Box 2:16)
    - American Brass Co., Divisions, 1958 (Box 3:17)
    - American Brass Co., District offices and warehouses, 1899-1960 (Box 3:18)
  - Subseries C: Pope Subject Files, undated, 1351-1960
    - A
      - A.H. Wells, Inc., 1886-1912, 1950-1960 (Box 3:19)
      - Ansonia, 1836-1903 (Box 3:19)
      - Aluminum- period divisions, 1827-1908 (Box 3:19)
      - American Brass Association, 1871 (Box 3:19)
      - Amalgamated Copper Co., Ansonia, CT, 1899-1901 (Box 3:19)
      - Aluminum Brass and Bronze Company, 1888-1889 (Box 3:19)
      - Anaconda Alloys Corporation, 1943-1950 (Box 3:19)
      - Anaconda Copper Mining Company, 1929-1944 (Box 3:19)
      - Articles (various subjects), 1934-1952 (Box 3:19)
    - B
      - Benedict Nickel, 1836-1899 (Box 3:20)
      - Buildings ( American Cap and Flask Co., Waterbury Brass Goods Corporation, Waterbury Brass Co., undated (Box 3:20)
      - Basic Magnesium, Inc., undated (Box 3:20)
      - Brass and Copper Mills, 1807-1860 (Box 3:20)
      - Beryllium Copper products, 1930-1944 (Box 3:20)
      - Brooker, Charles F. (remarks), 1920 (Box 3:20)
      - Brass industry (development), 1939 (Box 3:20)
      - Benson, Howard R., 1936 (Box 3:20)
    - C
      - Charter, undated (Box 3:20)
      - Chronology, 1893-1942 (Box 3:20)
      - Continuous (semi) casting and rolling, undated (Box 3:20)
      - Copper mining, 1632-1719, 1845-1903 (Box 3:20)
      - "Crypt of civilization", undated (Box 3:20)
      - Copper, 1938 (Box 3:20)
      - Canada Strip Mill, Ltd., 1946 (Box 3:20)
      - Capital Stock Authorization, 1893-1903 (Box 3:20)
      - Conklin Brass & Copper Company, 1860-1923 (Box 3:20)
      - Cuspidors, 1913, 1922 (Box 3:20)
      - Old Line Connecticut firms, 1767-1807 (Box 3:20)
      - Copper and Brass Research Association, undated (Box 3:20)
      - Coe, John Allen (the elder), 1947 (Box 3:20)
      - Coe, John Allen (I), 1948 (Box 3:20)
      - Coe, Israel, 1948 (Box 3:20)
      - Coe, Lyman W., 1948 (Box 3:20)
      - Copper Wire, 1876-1900, 1926 (Box 3:20)
    - D
      - Dates, 1800-1892 (Box 3:20)
      - Development (early) of American Industry, 1800-1892 (Box 3:20)
      - Distributors, 1855-1899 (Box 3:20)
      - District offices, 1912, 1922-1940, 1957 (Box 3:20)
      - Daguerreotypes, historical data, 1856-1890 (Box 3:20)
    - E
      - Extrusion process for brass alloys, 1883-1910 (Box 3:20)
      - Electro-deposited copper, 1922-1936 (Box 3:20)
      - Electro-sheet copper, 1925-1960 (Box 3:20)
      - Executive officers, 1899-1955 (Box 3:20)
      - Eyelet machines, 1860-1866 (Box 3:20)
    - F
      - Floor areas, American Brass Co., 1958 (Box 3:21)
      - Farrel-Birmingham Co., Inc., 1836, 1848 (Box 3:21)
      - "Firsts", 1954 (Box 3:21)
    - G
      - Grilley's Button Shop, 1707-1937 (Box 3:21)
      - "Good Old Days", 1899-1934 (Box 3:21)
    - H
      - History, 1812, 1940 (Box 3:21)
      - Historical lore, 1947 (Box 3:21)
    - I
      - Industry-Directories, 1831, 1890 (Box 3:21)
    - J
      - Judd, Clark S., 1944 (Box 3:21)
    - K
      - Kelly, C. F., 1955 (Box 3:21)
    - L
      - Laboratory (first) for Non-Ferrous metals, 1960 (Box 3:21)
      - Library, 1905-1960 (Box 3:21)
      - Licenses, 1938 (Box 3:21)
      - Longevity Accounts (customers), 1903-1960 (Box 3:21)
    - M
      - Main office, 1906-1913 (Box 3:21)
      - Mannesmann Tube Rolling process, 1883-1890 (Box 3:21)
      - Mannesmann machine, 1885-1912 (Box 3:21)
      - Miscellaneous notes, 1907-1954 (Box 3:21)
      - Muntz Metal, 1832 (Box 3:21)
    - N
      - Naugatuck, 1948 (Box 3:21)
      - Navy "E" Awards, 1942 (Box 3:21)
      - Nickel and nickel silver, 1950, 1959 (Box 3:21)
      - New Haven and Baltimore Button Co., 1713-1808 (Box 3:21)
      - New Haven Copper Company, 1848-1935 (Box 3:21)
      - Non-ferrous industry, 1960 (Box 3:21)
    - O
      - Office hours, 1902-1960 (Box 3:21)
      - Original tenants, American Brass Co. building, 1956 (Box 3:21)
      - Old ledgers, journals, cash books, etc. compilation, 1842-1900 (Box 3:21)
    - P
      - Photos-historical, 1959 (Box 3:22)
      - Pipe, 1921-1939 (Box 3:22)
      - Policy of Manufacturing raw and semi-finished materials, 1949 (Box 3:22)
      - Price control, 1941-1943 (Box 3:22)
      - Price lists, 1853-1871 (Box 3:22)
      - Production, 1901-1919 (Box 3:22)
      - Policy-sales, 1949 (Box 3:22)
    - R
      - Raritan Copper Works, 1890-1899 (Box 3:22)
      - "Rediscovering Connecticut", 1948 (Box 3:22)
      - Research and Product development, 1958-1960 (Box 3:22)
      - Rolled and sheet brass prices, 1853-1889 (Box 3:22)
    - S
      - Sales Trainee program, 1956 (Box 3:22)
      - Seymour Manufacturing Company, 1880-1960 (Box 3:22)
      - Significance of slogan "From Mine to Consumer", 1926 (Box 3:22)
      - Somers Brass Company, 1830-1890, 1909 (Box 3:22)
      - Star Pin Company, 1886, 1926, 1941, 1955 (Box 3:22)
      - Stockholders, as of February 1, 1902 (Box 3:22)
    - T
      - Technical control, 1879, 1955 (Box 3:22)
      - Telephones, 1875-1892 (Box 3:22)
      - Terms, 1945-1960 (Box 3:22)
      - Torrington (Box 3:22)
        - History of, 1732-1923
        - (How it got its name), undated
      - Trademarks, 1922-1925, 1959 (Box 3:22)
      - Tube-Admirality Condenser, 1894-1904, 1936 (Box 3:22)
      - Tube- Brass and gold, 1869, 1885, 1904 (Box 3:22)
      - Tube- Seamless Cupro-nickel Condenser Tubes, 1838-1850 (Box 3:22)
      - Tube- Water Tube and Pipe, 1889-1936 (Box 3:22)
      - Turner, Elisha and Philander Hine, 1848-1938 (Box 3:22)
    - U
      - U.S. Patent Office, 1780 (Box 3:22)
    - W
      - Warehouses and mill depots, 1899-1959 (Box 3:22)
      - Wire, 1892-1915, 1952 (Box 3:22)
      - Wire (drawing of), 1351-1791, 1825-1937 (Box 3:22)
    - XYZ
      - "Yankee Iron" reprint, 1952 (Box 3:22)